## **André Pena**

I'm self-motivated and passionate about software development and technology in general. I enjoy learning new frameworks, libraries and tools. I like to participate in online communities like Stackoverflow, contribute to open-source on GitHub, and lately I've passing a fair amount of time solving algorithm problems on Hackerrank to stay sharp and sometimes I post about my life / software experience on Medium.

Professionally, it's been 11 years implementing web applications, frameworks and libraries, mainly using React, Redux, jQuery, TypeScript, JavaScript and SASS in the client-side, and ASP.NET and Node on the server.

I have certifications in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, C# and ASP.NET.

Other relevant stuff about me:

- I have experience working with large scale enterprise apps.
- I have experience working remotely in culturally diverse teams.
- I have experience being a technical leader and software architect.
- I really like and take seriously user experience and design (CSS and SASS).

I speak English and Portuguese fluently, and I can communicate in Spanish.

Check out my website for more info: http://andrerpena.me

#### **Technical Skills**

Likes:

.net c# javascript asp.net-mvc entity-framework git agile azure saas rethinkdb ninject signalr twitter-bootstrap

node.js reactjs redux ecmascript-6 gulp html css mocha karma-runner scrum docker vagrant

Dislikes: php

Experience

## Full Stack Sofware Engineer – Bluestone Group reactjs, typescript, javascript, ecmascript-6, c#, asp.net-mvc, .net

Jun 2017 → Current

Implement loan software for brokers world-wide. Even though I'm a full-stack developer, I'm working mainly in the client side using React / Redux / TypeScript. The server stack is ASP.NET MVC, Entity Framework and SQL Server.

# **Technical software architect / Lead web developer** – Thomson Reuters c#, html, entity-framework, javascript, css, asp.net, .net, sql-server, node.js, reactjs, redux, python

Sep 2012 → Jun 2017

#### Responsibilities:

- Architect a framework for implementing large-scale data-centric business applications.
- Help creating POCs and implementing such framework.
- Provide guidance for developers when it comes to best practices, scalability, extensibility and maintainabilty.
- Drive innovation and propose modern and efficient solutions according to evolving industry standards.

#### Challenges of the projects we create:

- Create a platform for making it easy to create SCRUD heavy applications.
- Make the applications localizable, both in terms of translation, number/date formats and multi-currency support, as well as providing a way for the regions to customize the views and behavior.

#### Examples of problems we tackle:

- How to implement localization, including time zones, currency, number and date formats and translations?
- How to make the application modular? That is, how to deliver only some particular modules depending on the customer demands?
- How to deploy an application in a country that have variations in the data fields, business rules and texts. How to implement the differences without forking the original application?
- How to make the applications extensible to the end user? A key point to go global with a line of business App is
  to give the most flexibility to the end user. He/she must have the ability to customize texts, change the application
  data fields and manipulate the layout.

#### Tech lead / Senior Web Developer - Novaprolink Tecnologia

.net. c#, asp.net-mvc, entity-framework, mstest

We migrated our line-of-business web framework to ASP.NET MVC using Entity Framework as the ORM solution. I was the tech lead in the process, helping creating the framework to support the developers and making them productive.

I was responsible for:

- General application layout (HTML, CSS and JavaScript)
- jQuery plug-ins development
- ASP.NET MVC helpers, specially to make it easy to create data-driven forms, and integrating with the jQuery plugins.
- Entity Framework architecture.
- · Access Control.
- Licensing
- Reporting
- MSTest architecture.

#### Web Developer - Novaprolink Tecnologia

Jun 2007 → May 2009

Jun 2009 → Aug 2012

.net, c#, webforms, winforms, designer, visual-studio-addins, orm

We started developing a framework for creating line-of-business / model-driven apps for ASP.NET WebForms. I was involved in every aspect of the design, from the ground up:

- · Visual Studio Add-ins development.
- Data Access Layer with DevExpress eXpress Persistent Objects.
- Web-Control development, involving both client and server side, emphasizing rich data-aware capabilities.
- Web-Control designers development (Windows Forms applications aimed to enhance the developer experience while designing controls)
- · Application flow: Authentication, Authorization, Access Control, Licencing, Testing...

This project has been deprecated in favor of a newer one. I'm no longer active with ASP.NET Webforms and Visual Studio Addins development

Intern – JGP

adobe-flex, java, action-script, cairngorm

I was a intern working with Adobe Flex and Java for a stock market consulting company. I worked with both the front-end and back-end. This period allowed me to get very familiar with object orientation and web-services.

#### Education

### Bachelors in Information Science (Currently studying remotely) – Universidade Estácio de Sá

2015 → Current

#### Certifications

### Microsoft Specialist: Programming in HTML5 with JavaScript and CSS3 html5, css3, javascript

Nov 2016 → Current

Microsoft Specialist: Programming in C#

Sep 2016 → Current

### c#, .net

Microsoft Certified Professional c#, asp.net, .net

Apr 2012 → Current

### Microsoft® Certified Technology Specialist: .NET Framework 4, Web Applications

c#, asp.net, asp.net-mvc, .net

Jan 2011 → Current

#### **Projects & Interests**

#### Stack Overflow - https://stackoverflow.com/users/192729/andrerpena

Oct 2009 → Current

Written 325 answers. Active in reactis, .net, asp.net-mvc-4, c#, css and 8 other tags.

### **react-mde** – https://github.com/andrerpena/react-mde node, ecmascript-6, reactjs, gulp

Dec 2016 → Current

React Markdown Editor inspired by GitHub

redux-autoform-bootstrap-ui – https://github.com/andrerpena/redux-autoform-bootstrap-ui iavascript

 $\textit{Jul 2016} \rightarrow \textit{Current}$ 

Bootstrap UI extension for redux-autoform

	<pre>redux-autoform - https://github.com/andrerpena/redux-autoform javascript</pre>	Jul 2016 → Current
	Create Redux-Forms dynamically out of metadata	
	L1PM – https://github.com/andrerpena/legalone-pacote-melhorias vue.js, sass, node.js, gulp, google-chrome-extension	Jul 2016 → Current
	A Chrome Extension to add user experience and new features to Legal One, the project I work for on my day job.	
	<pre>quotr – https://github.com/andrerpena/quotr javascript</pre>	Oct 2015 → Current
	A Node.js CLI for displaying stock exchange quotes	
	react-metaform – https://github.com/gearz-lab/react-metaform javascript	Aug 2015 → Current
	A library for dynamically generating React forms out of metadata	
	<pre>chatjs - https://github.com/andrerpena/chatjs typescript</pre>	Sep 2014 → Current
	Platform-independent jQuery plugin for chatting	
	SmartRecords – https://github.com/andrerpena/SmartRecords c#	Aug 2013 → Current
	A simple .NET report generation library	
	Cerebello – https://github.com/andrerpena/Cerebello c#	Apr 2012 → Current
	Medical practice administration system	
Others	Background – Background	
	I'm a full-stack web developer with experience in C#/ASP.NET and Node.js, as well as HTML, CSS and JavaScript/jQuery/React	
	e-mail: andrerpena at gmail.com	
Readings	C# in Depth, 3rd Edition – Jon Skeet – http://www.amazon.com/Depth-3rd-Edition-Jon-Skeet/dp/161729134X	
	Secrets of the JavaScript Ninja – John Resig, Bear Bibeault – http://www.amazon.com/Secrets-JavaScript-Ninja-John-Resig/dp/193398869X	
Tools	First Computer: 486 DX2 Favorite Editor: WebStorm	